<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Andrew R. Bock</origin>
        <origin>James A. Falcone</origin>
        <origin>Gretchen Oelsner</origin>
        <pubdate>2018</pubdate>
        <title>Estimates of Road Salt Application across the Conterminous United States, 1992-2015</title>
        <geoform>Geostationary Earth Orbit Tagged Image File Format</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
          <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://doi.org/10.5066/P96IX385</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Annual estimates of road salt application were developed for the conterminous United States for the calendar years 1992 through 2015.  The final dataset consists of 24 rasters in Geostationary Earth Orbit Tagged Image File Format (GeoTIFF), one for each year from 1992 through 2015. The final estimates (in pounds) were derived from several data sources, which include road density and proportion of developed land use, depth and spatial extent of long-term snowfall, and the production and distribution of salt sources by state.  The extent is the conterminous United States, and the spatial resolution is one-square kilometer.</abstract>
      <purpose>The purpose of this dataset is to provide spatially-distributed estimates of road salt application across the conterminous United States (CONUS).</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19920101</begdate>
          <enddate>20151231</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-125.2441</westbc>
        <eastbc>-65.6543</eastbc>
        <northbc>49.4678</northbc>
        <southbc>24.4868</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>USGS Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>salinity</themekey>
        <themekey>geospatial datasets</themekey>
        <themekey>surface-water quality</themekey>
        <themekey>ground transportation</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>USGS Metadata Identifier</themekt>
        <themekey>USGS:5b15a50ce4b092d9651e22b9</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>USGS Thesaurus</placekt>
        <placekey>United States</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>none</accconst>
    <useconst>none</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Andrew Bock</cntper>
          <cntorg>Southwest Region</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>Hydrologist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>Mail Stop 415, W 6th Ave Kipling St</address>
          <city>Lakewood</city>
          <state>CO</state>
          <postal>80225</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>303-236-6875</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>abock@usgs.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <datacred>Funding to support this dataset was provided by the U.S. Geological Survey National Water-Quality Program’s National Water-Quality Assessment Project.</datacred>
    <native>The salt data were compiled using microsoft excel and converted to raster format using the R Project for statistical computing, version 3.4.  The remaining data processing (processing steps 1 through 4) and the generation of the final annual road salt volume rasters (contained within 1992_2015.zip) were generated using ArcGIS version 10.5.0.6491.  The zip file (139,647 KB) contains 24 grids in geostationary earth orbit tagged image file format (GeoTIFF) ranging from 4.727 to 7.55 megabytes.  Each grid contains an accompanying metadata file (xml) that is a duplicate of this file.</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>Road salt estimates for each year were summarized by state to ensure that they match the original state-by-state volume estimates published in the U.S. Geological Survey minerals yearbooks.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>No formal logical accuracy tests were conducted</logic>
    <complete>Dataset is considered complete for the information presented, as described in the abstract. Users are advised to read the rest of the metadata record carefully for additional details.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>No formal positional accuracy tests were conducted</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>No formal positional accuracy tests were conducted</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Kostick, Dennis S.; Bolen, Wallace P.</origin>
            <pubdate>2015</pubdate>
            <title>U.S. Bureau of Mines, U.S. Geological Survey Minerals Yearbook - Salt</title>
            <geoform>publication</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Bureau of Mines, US Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>The yearbooks for 1993 through 2011 were compiled and written by Dennis S. Kostick and from 2012 onwards by Wallace P.  Bolen.  The yearbooks for 1995 through 2015 were published by the U.S. Geological Survey.  The 1993 and 1994 yearbooks were originally published by the U.S. Bureau of Mines.</othercit>
            <onlink>https://minerals.usgs.gov/minerals/pubs/commodity/salt/index.html#mcs</onlink>
            <onlink>http://digital.library.wisc.edu/1711.dl/EcoNatRes.MinYB1993v1</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>19920101</begdate>
              <enddate>20151231</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Salt</srccitea>
        <srccontr>The salt yearbooks are used for estimation of the per-state/annual volume of salt used for ice control (Processing Step 1).  With the exception of 2015, the annual salt estimates for each year are always derived from the revised estimates of the yearbook of the following year (for example, estimates for 1994 are taken from the revised 1994 estimates available in the 1995 minerals yearbook).</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>National Highway Traffic Safety Administration</origin>
            <pubdate>2015</pubdate>
            <title>ODI Resume, Investigation EA11-001, Brake line corrosion failure</title>
            <geoform>online</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Washington D.C.</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Department of Transportation</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>https://www.safercar.gov/staticfiles/safercar/pdf/EA11001-Close.pdf</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>20110105</begdate>
              <enddate>20150408</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NHTSC</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Identification of states used for three road salt tiers (Processing Step 1).</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>James A. Falcone</origin>
            <pubdate>2015</pubdate>
            <title>U.S. conterminous wall-to-wall anthropogenic land use trends (NWALT), 1974–2012</title>
            <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
              <publish>US Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>http://dx.doi.org/10.3133/ds948</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>19740101</begdate>
              <enddate>20120101</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NWALT</srccitea>
        <srccontr>NWALT grids were used to create road densities for 1992 and 2002 (Processing Step 1).</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>National Climatic Data Center (NCDC)</origin>
            <pubdate>2002</pubdate>
            <title>Climate atlas of the United States</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Asheville, NC</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Department of Commerce</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>https://www.ncei.noaa.gov/data/climate-maps-deprecated/access/</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>19610101</begdate>
              <enddate>19901231</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Snow</srccitea>
        <srccontr>The conterminous United States-extent snow depth shapefile was used to create snow depth raster (Processing Step 2).</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Forest Service</origin>
            <pubdate>2018</pubdate>
            <title>Motor Vehicle Use Map: Roads</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Washington, D.C.</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Forest Service</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>https://data.fs.usda.gov/geodata/edw/datasets.php?xmlKeyword=Roads</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>20180305</begdate>
              <enddate>20180305</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>MVU</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Used in the estimation of the density of roads that receive ice control treatment (Processing Step 3).</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Forest Service</origin>
            <pubdate>2018</pubdate>
            <title>S_USA.RoadCore_FS.gdb</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Washington, D.C.</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Forest Service</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>https://data.fs.usda.gov/geodata/edw/edw_resources/meta/S_USA.RoadCore_FS.xml</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>20180305</begdate>
              <enddate>20180305</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>National Forest System Roads</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Used in the estimation of the density of roads that receive ice control treatment (Processing Step 3).</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Census Bureau</origin>
            <pubdate>2013</pubdate>
            <title>2013 Topologically Integrated Geographic Encoding and Reference (TIGER) Geodatabase</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Washington, D.C.</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Census Bureau</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>https://www.census.gov/geo/maps-data/data/tiger-geodatabases.html</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>20130101</begdate>
              <enddate>20131231</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>TIGER</srccitea>
        <srccontr>The TIGER roads feature class was used in the estimation of the density of roads that receive ice control treatment (Processing Step 3).</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>David W. Anning</origin>
            <origin>Marilyn E. Flynn</origin>
            <pubdate>2014</pubdate>
            <title>Dissolved-solids sources, loads, yields, and concentrations in streams of the conterminous United States</title>
            <geoform>publication</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
              <publish>US Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>http://dx.doi.org/10.3133/sir20145012</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>Digital and/or Hardcopy</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2001</begdate>
              <enddate>2012</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Anning and Flynn</srccitea>
        <srccontr>The methodology used to derive road deicing and ice control volumes used to create this dataset was modified from this report.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>R Core Team</origin>
            <pubdate>2016</pubdate>
            <title>R: A language and environment for statistical computing</title>
            <geoform>application/service</geoform>
            <onlink>http://www.R-project.org/</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>Digital and/or Hardcopy</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2017</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>R Core Team</srccitea>
        <srccontr>The program R was used to process the salt data.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Step 1:  Volumes of rock and solar salt by state were compiled for the calendar years1992 through 2015 from Tables 6/7/8 of the U.S. Bureau of Mines, USGS Minerals Yearbook (Salt) (Kostick, 1992-2011; Bolen 2013-2015). The table is consistently titled "Distribution of Domestic and Imported Evaporated and Rock Salt in the United States, By Destination" through all yearbooks. Rock and solar salt sources were used as components for road salt. Definition of these salt sources are found in the salt yearbook introduction sections from the year 2002 onwards. The proportion of solar salt used for ice control over the period of record was .194 based on Tables 5/6/7 (titled "Distribution of Domestic and Imported Data by Producers in the United States by End Use and Type" in all yearbooks). Proportional factors were used to weight each state's salt volume for ice control. The use of these proportional factors to determine an ice control volume used for each state was modified from the methodology originally described in Anning and Flynn (2014). Each state's annual solar salt distribution was multiplied by the proportional value of 0.2 to get the volume of solar salt used for ice control. The proportion of rock salt used for ice control was varied by state based on each state's location within or proximity to a region of the United States commonly referred to as 'The Salt Belt'. The National Highway Traffic Safety Commission has regarded states within this region as "salt states" for investigation of automobile corrosion issues (NHTSC, 2015). The proportional value of 0.9 was used for states within the salt belt (Tier 1, see 'RoadSalt_Tiers.xls'), the proportional value of 0.4 was used for mountain belt states and states adjacent to the salt belt (Tier 2), and all other states were assigned a proportional value of 0.1 (Tier 3). The weighted solar and rock salt volumes were added for each state for each year and multiplied by 2,204,620 to convert from thousands of metric tons to pounds. Final raster formats were derived in the geostationary Earth orbit tagged image file format (GeoTIFF), with the same spatial resolution and extent as the grids in NWALT (Falcone, 2015). Salt volumes by state were first converted to an ESRI shapefile using R (R Core Team, 2016) and then to a raster using ArcGIS version 10.5.0.6491. Unless otherwise noted, all remaining processing steps were completed in ArcGIS.</procdesc>
        <srcused>Salt</srcused>
        <srcused>NHTSC</srcused>
        <srcused>NWALT</srcused>
        <srcused>Anning and Flynn</srcused>
        <procdate>2018</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Step 2: Total snowfall depth estimates from the NOAA 1961-1990 climate normals (Snow) (NCDC, 2002) were converted from shapefile to GeoTIFF format, with the same spatial resolution and extent as the grids in NWALT (Falcone, 2015). The median value of the polygon attribute field "INCHES", which exists as a text field representing a range of total snow fall, was coded as the raster value in 32-bit float format. Polygons with the highest snow fall category ("I &gt; 72.0") were coded with '72'.</procdesc>
        <srcused>Snow</srcused>
        <srcused>NWALT</srcused>
        <procdate>2018</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Step 3:  A grid (in GeoTIFF format matching the NWALT spatial resolution and extent) of the density of road types likely to receive ice control treatment was derived from several data sources. The TIGER national roads feature class from 2013 was used as the roads source (U.S. Census Bureau, 2013). The length of road types C3061 (Cul-de-sac), C3062 (Traffic Circle), S1100 (Primary Road), S1200 (Secondary Road), S1400 (Local Neighborhood Road, Rural Road, City Street), S1630 (Ramp), S1640 (Service Drive) and S1780 (Parking Lot Road) were summarized (in kilometers) for each 1 square kilometer grid cell.  The total length of primary roads was multiplied by 2 and secondary roads by 1.5 to account for greater number of lanes and usage for these features (U.S. Census Bureau, 2013). The density of available sources of unimproved federal roads were summarized (MVU and National Forest System Roads) (U.S. Forest Service, 2018) and subtracted from the road densities derived from the 2013 TIGER data source. The NWALT dataset (Falcone, 2015) was used to create temporally-varying estimates of road density over the period of record covered by the salt data (1992-2015). NWALT is a national extent set of grids that describe anthropogenic land use for five different time periods (1974, 1982, 1992, 2002, and 2012). The proportion of urban and developed land use per square kilometer across the CONUS was first determined using the NWALT grids for 1992, 2002, and 2012. This was used to create temporally-varying road density grids for 1992 through 2015. The road density grid for the years 1993 through 1997 (proximate years to 1992) was derived by multiplying the road density grid derived from TIGER by the proportional change in urban/developed land between 1992 and 2012 (TIGER road density x developed-urban1992/developed-urban2012). The road density grid for 1998 through 2007 was derived by weighting the TIGER 2013 road density grid by changes in urban land use between 2002 and 2012 (TIGER road density x developed-urban1992/developed-urban2012). The initial road density grid developed for 2013 was used for the remaining years of 2008 through 2015.</procdesc>
        <srcused>NWALT</srcused>
        <srcused>TIGER</srcused>
        <srcused>MVU</srcused>
        <srcused>S_USA.RoadCore_FS</srcused>
        <procdate>2018</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Step 4:  The snow depth GeoTIFF (Step 2) was multiplied by each of the three road density grids to create a measure of total depth over the length of road within each grid cell that is likely to receive ice control treatment (snow2road). This numbers were then summarized for each state for each of the three road density grids (stateSum). A per-grid cell proportion of snow depth on the roadways (propSnow) was calculated by dividing each grid cell's snow2road value by the stateSum raster. The estimated, total road salt volume for each state for each year (Step 1) was then multiplied by the propSnow grid. This resulted in a final raster, which allocated road salt to each grid cell based on the proportional values of both road length and snow depth. Raster layers for all 48 states and DC were then mosaiced together to create a final seamless CONUS raster for each year (XXXX.tif, XXXX indicating the calendar year ranging from 1992 to 2015).</procdesc>
        <procdate>2018</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>Albers Conical Equal Area</mapprojn>
          <albers>
            <stdparll>29.5</stdparll>
            <stdparll>45.5</stdparll>
            <longcm>-96.0</longcm>
            <latprjo>23.0</latprjo>
            <feast>0.0</feast>
            <fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
          </albers>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>1000.0</absres>
            <ordres>1000.0</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>XXXX.tif</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Estimated annual volume of road salt applied (pounds).  'XXXX' is the chronological series of years from 1992 to 2015.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>Producer defined.</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Value</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Pounds of road salt applied.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer defined.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>1582037.625</rdommax>
            <attrunit>Pounds</attrunit>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>RoadSalt_Tiers.xlsx</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Road Salt tiers and proportions assigned to the 48 states of the conterminous United States and the District of Columbia</enttypd>
        <enttypds>producer defined.</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Abbrev</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>State abbreviation</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>American National Standards Institute</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>INCITS 38:2009</codesetn>
            <codesets>https://www.census.gov/geo/reference/ansi_statetables.html</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>State</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>State name</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>American National Standards Institute</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>INCITS 38:2009</codesetn>
            <codesets>https://www.census.gov/geo/reference/ansi_statetables.html</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Tier</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Road salt tier that state is classified by.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1</edomv>
            <edomvd>Road Salt Tier 1 (0.1 proportional value)</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>2</edomv>
            <edomvd>Road Salt Tier 2 (0.4 proportional value)</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>3</edomv>
            <edomvd>Road Salt Tier 3 (0.9 proportional value)</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Proportion</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Proportional value used to weight ice control volume.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom></udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>GS ScienceBase</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>Denver Federal Center, Building 810, Mail Stop 302</address>
          <city>Denver</city>
          <state>CO</state>
          <postal>80225</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-888-275-8747</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>sciencebase@usgs.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>Unless otherwise stated, all data, metadata and related materials are considered to satisfy the quality standards relative to the purpose for which the data were collected. Although these data and associated metadata have been reviewed for accuracy and completeness and approved for release by the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), no warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the display or utility of the data for other purposes, nor on all computer systems, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>Digital Data</formname>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>https://doi.org/10.5066/P96IX385</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20200826</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Andy Bock</cntper>
          <cntorg>Southwest Region</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>Hydrologist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>Mail Stop 415, W 6th Ave Kipling St</address>
          <city>Lakewood</city>
          <state>CO</state>
          <postal>80225</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>303-236-6875</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>abock@usgs.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
